<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Paris | Linkage Disequilibrium]]></title>
  <link href="http://www.sahirbhatnagar.com/blog/categories/paris/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://www.sahirbhatnagar.com/"/>
  <updated>2014-09-05T18:25:02-04:00</updated>
  <id>http://www.sahirbhatnagar.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Sahir Rai Bhatnagar]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[sahir.bhatnagar@gmail.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[A Day in Paris]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.sahirbhatnagar.com/blog/2014/08/18/a-day-in-paris/"/>
    <updated>2014-08-18T05:20:48-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.sahirbhatnagar.com/blog/2014/08/18/a-day-in-paris</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>We started the day with a walking tour with <a href="www.culturefishtours.com">Culture Fish</a>. It’s a relatively new company started by three American siblings who have a French mother. Like most of its kind, the tour is free though tipping is expected. They offer two tours: main events which started at La Cite metro and monmarte, we took the former.</p>
<!-- more -->

<p>It was a good intro to Paris tour covering the main attractions such as Notre Dame Basilica, Louvre, Tour Eiffel, La Seine, le pont des amoureux, l’Hotel de Ville. Our guide Pierre gave a very nice clear overview of the different time periods in Parisian history and the different peoples that occupied it.</p>
<p>A unique feature of this tour, and the story behind the company’s name, was the stories about culture clashes, i.e., when people from around the world intereact with the locals. For example, Parisians keep their voices down and see screaming or yelling as a sign of disrespect while in other cultures, like Indians or Italians, speaking loudly is the norm. They also expect you to greet them by saying <em>Bonjour Monsieur</em> or <em>Bonjour Madame</em>. Locals also love to relax; something us North Americans might not be accustomed to doing. Life is alot slower here according to Pierre. He told us when he was trying to get some promotional items for his company, it took him forever to find anyone with a website (which is unheared of nowadays in Canada and the US). He said things are done more by word of mouth.</p>
<p>Pierre also gave us some tips on what not to say when speaking Quebec French. Never ask <em>ca va</em> on the first meeting; it’s too personal of a question. Never use <em>tu</em> or <em>toi</em>, instead use <em>vous</em>.</p>
<p>The sights in Paris are overwhelming, even the second time around. I still like the Arc de Triomphe the most. Even though climbing the stairs to the top of it will set you back 10 euro, its worth it compared to going up the tour Eiffel.</p>
<p>The most dissapointing part of Paris was by far the food. Maybe because we have such high expectations for a city like Paris, or maybe because we are spoiled in Montreal. Maybe we didn’t look hard enough, but then again, you shouldn’t have to look very hard in such a big city. If you’re ever planning to go to Paris, try hard in advance to look for non-touristic restaurants, recommended by locals. Also be aware that street signs are non-existent in Paris. They are painted onto the corner building which gets really confusing with all the roundabouts and multi-intersections… Something we take for granted I guess in Canada.</p>
<p>We stayed at an Airbnb place near metro Guy Moquet. The area was nice, with a wine shop, grocery store and supermarket nearby. Its crazy how they sell hard liquor at the grocery store.</p>]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Travelling to Paris]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.sahirbhatnagar.com/blog/2014/08/16/travelling-to-paris/"/>
    <updated>2014-08-16T10:03:52-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.sahirbhatnagar.com/blog/2014/08/16/travelling-to-paris</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Our Europe 2014 trip plan:</p>
<p><img src="/images/europe2014/paris/map.png" title="[CDG]" ></p>
<!-- more -->

<p>We took the evening flight from Montreal Trudeau (YUL) to Paris Charles de Gaulle (CDG).</p>
<p><img src="/images/europe2014/paris/IMG_6384.JPG" title="[CDG]" ></p>
<p>Here’s the <em>before</em> picutre:</p>
<p><img src="/images/europe2014/paris/IMG_6379.JPG" title="[CDG]" ></p>
<p>I tried to sleep as little as possible in the nights leading up to the flight to try and counteract the jet-lag but it didn’t work. We had trouble sleeping in the plane so we watched Hunger Games: Catching Fire…twice. It’s actually a pretty interesting movie; a comic book which depicts human nature in the face of opression. The plane food was terrible as expected. Note to self: ask for the Hindu option next time.</p>
<p><img src="/images/europe2014/paris/IMG_6386.JPG" title="[CDG]" ></p>
<p>We landed in Paris on August 13th at 6 am, and took the <a href="http://www.aeroportsdeparis.fr/ADP/en-GB/Passagers/Access-maps-car-parks/Paris-CDG/Access/public-transport/paris-cdg-roissybus.htm">RoissyBus</a> from Terminal 3 to Opera metro.</p>
<p><img src="/images/europe2014/paris/IMG_6388.JPG" title="[CDG]" ></p>
<p>This was a nice bus ride, and allowed you to see the <strong>normal</strong> part of Paris: Peugeot cars, highways, people going to work in the morning, apartments, factories. It’s a nice dose of reality and reminds you that Paris is more than just huge monuments, overpriced shopping and a tourist mayhem. Here’s a picture of Karen thouroughly enjoying the RoissyBus.</p>
<p><img src="/images/europe2014/paris/IMG_6389.JPG" title="[CDG]" ></p>]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
